[The Unclouded Soul]
[Episode 21]
If your heart is not sincere,
your life will end.
But Exalted Immortal...
Without destiny for immortality,
it'll all just be a fleeting dream.
Even the Exalted Immortal cannot save you.
Why is that?
Those hundred maidens sent last time
had too much selfish desire
and too many distracting thoughts,
making you unworthy of the Yuli Spring.
Please, Exalted Immortal,
do not be angry.
Since ancient times,
human hearts are hard to fathom.
If any wretched servant
has offended Exalted Immortal,
I will punish them severely.
But everyone in the Tiansheng Dynasty
has been sincere to Exalted Immortal—
the heavens can be the witness.
If you claim your heart is sincere,
then cut it out and show it to me.
Didn't you believe that by drinking
from the Yuli Spring,
you had already achieved immortality?
If what you drank
was truly the Yuli Spring,
you wouldn't die.
Shall we test it?
I was foolish.
Please, Exalted Immortal,
give me another chance.
I will surely show Exalted Immortal
my sincerity.
Though you've made a mistake,
there is someone
truly sincere by your side.
He is the key to finding the Yuli Spring.
Please enlighten me, Exalted Immortal.
Bingzhu of the Feiyu Guard
is worthy of great purpose.
Where is Bingzhu?
Your Majesty,
Bingzhu is imprisoned
in the Imperial Prison,
awaiting execution
at noon as you commanded.
No!
Support Admin Watch on
kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
My Lord,
it's already past 9 a.m.
We should escort the prisoner
to the Meridian Gate now.
Haven't you found that demoness yet?
No.
We cannot allow any complications.
Let's just deal with him here.
Here?
I'm afraid
this goes against His Majesty's wishes,
My Lord.
His Majesty's wishes?
His Majesty's wishes are unfathomable.
What's the point
of following so many imperial edicts?
I spoke out of turn.
Forgive my impertinence.
It's all up to My Lord to decide.
What His Majesty wants to see
is Bingzhu
beheaded in front of everyone.
But Lord Bingzhu
has drunk from the Yuli Spring.
I fear beheading alone
won't eliminate the root of the problem.
That would truly go against
His Majesty's wishes.
Go fetch some mulberry paper.
Let's suffocate Lord Bingzhu
to death.
Yes.
A promotion to a first-class official
makes you worry-free
about food and clothing.
With new titles bestowed,
may it be an auspicious omen!
Put another one.
The imperial edict has arrived!
By the mandate of heaven,
the Emperor decrees:
in consideration of
the many loyal years of service
of the accused,
Bingzhu of the Feiyu Guard,
who devoted himself to slaying demons,
I wish for peace throughout the land,
and hope for his sincere repentance.
I hereby pardon Bingzhu and summon him
to the West Garden for an audience.
So it is decreed.
I, your humble subject,
receive this edict.
Lord Bingzhu,
your palanquin is ready.
Please come this way.
As long as the heart remains,
nightmares can still occur.
From now on,
at least no one can use
nightmare techniques against me anymore.
Your brother will be safe now.
I have become a spirit.
Sooner or later,
you will kill me too—
just as you slaughter other demons.
There are too many things in this world
that need to be judged as right or wrong.
But the rights and wrongs
that don't concern me,
I no longer wish to argue about.
I will only care
about the three of us from now on.
How's that?
My Lord always knows what's best.
What's best?
This, of course!
I told Xiao Yao and Dali before
that rolling in the mud feels wonderful,
but they didn't believe me.
What did you say, My Lord?
Did you get the directions?
Yes, I did.
We're still hundreds of miles
from Mount Qingyuan.
Then let's keep moving.
My Lord,
the shopkeeper thought I was cute
and gave me a freshly steamed bun.
Would you like half?
No.
Walk faster.
Are we in such a hurry?
It's to make you stronger
so you won't end up
as someone else's bun filling.
How thoughtful you are, My Lord.
My Lord,
are we still going on foot?
What else?
If you could conjure some silver,
we could buy a carriage
and walk less.
The shopkeeper just now also said
taking the water route
is actually the fastest way.
Why didn't you say so earlier?
I just remembered it.
I shouldn't have let
a pig ask for directions.
My Lord.
I just finished eating,
but I feel hungry again.
Can I—
Watch out!
-Luoluo!
-My Lord!
Save me!
In broad daylight,
strolling through Black Wind Fortress
like this—
do you think we're all fast asleep?
What do you want?
Leave...
Leave some toll money.
You dare to rob me?
Have you really thought this through?
Boss.
I don't know what
this guy is up to.
Let's all attack together,
cut him into pieces,
and be done with it.
He's just a weak scholar,
and you're all scared?
Step back.
Let me handle him.
If we kill him,
how can we sell him for a good price?
I am a merchant's son.
The one you've captured
is my personal attendant.
I was passing through
with a family treasure
when I unfortunately
got separated from my family.
If you release my attendant,
this treasure
will be yours.
No, no!
I was wrong!
I'm not fighting anymore!
I'm sorry!
-Release him!
-I'm sorry.
Release him! Release him!
Release him.
Get lost.
My Lord, you're amazing!
Luoluo,
are you alright?
I'm fine.
My Lord,
why didn't you
just use your power to fight them
instead of making up stories?
Among humans,
we should use human methods.
We should adapt to our surroundings.
Hong Ye!
That makes sense.
Luoluo!
Xiao Yao?
Where are you going?
Back to Demons' Valley.
Are you done with your business?
You're leaving
without saying goodbye again.
In my current state,
I can't protect you properly.
This trip to Demons' Valley
will be extremely dangerous.
I don't even know if I'll return alive
or be able to stand by your side again.
If you come with me,
it will only bring you more danger.
So you just left me there alone?
I never wanted to leave you
or abandon you.
I only want to find
a safe place for you.
So I made a decision of my own accord.
Yes—of your own accord!
That's only what you think!
Do you know what I think?
Did you ever ask me?
You don't have the right to decide
whether I'll stay or not!
We've been
through life and death together.
What's there to fear?
Hong Ye, I'm asking you once.
In this life,
shall we never see each other ever again
or go through thick and thin together,
moving forward hand in hand—
make your choice.
For me,
my answer has always been only you.
Let's go,
back to Demons' Valley.
This is what you chose, right?
I wish for your heart alone,
and to never part
until we're old and gray.
I, your guilty subject, Bingzhu,
pay respects to Your Majesty.
Rise.
Be seated.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
My dear minister,
do you still resent me?
This guilty subject
would never dare.
I have always valued talent.
Otherwise, the court
would not have loyal ministers like you
who come from humble origins.
However,
the position of Feiyu Guard Demon Slayer
is no ordinary role.
On a smaller scale,
it concerns my personal safety.
On a larger scale, it bears
the responsibility for all people's lives.
I had to be
extremely cautious.
Do you understand?
This guilty subject
understands.
I have investigated.
This sea voyage,
although it failed to locate Yuli Spring,
the fault
was not yours.
As the Emperor,
I have the wisdom to judge character.
Sending you to the Imperial Prison
was your final test.
The Yuli Spring is crucial to the empire.
I need someone like you
who can withstand such trials
for me to feel at ease.
As of today,
I have no more doubts about you.
You need not address yourself
as "guilty subject" anymore.
Considering your years of loyal service
and excellent character,
I hereby name you Bulwark Duke.
In accordance with your noble rank,
I'll reward you with 100 acres of land,
and a thousand stones of grain.
How does that sound?
I
thank Your Majesty
for your generous grace.
Long live
Your Majesty!
Whether I can live long or not depends on
if you find the Yuli Spring or not.
Come.
Tell me everything in detail.
When you met the Exalted Immortal,
what did you talk about?
What does the Exalted Immortal prefer?
Your Majesty,
I
have only met the Exalted Immortal once.
The rules on the island were strict.
I was not allowed to move around freely.
So I
don't know the details.
Enough.
It's useless
to talk about the past now.
Since you are favored
by Exalted Immortal,
you should quickly find a way
to ask Exalted Immortal
what else I need to do
to be granted the Yuli Spring.
I
dare ask Your Majesty,
is the Exalted Immortal you speak of
still the one in this painting?
The Exalted Immortal
has many incarnations.
As long as she is still willing
to reveal herself to me,
immortality is still possible.
[Residence of the Bulwark Duke]
[Distinguish right from wrong]
Welcome home, Bulwark Duke.
My Lord!
I know my crime is unforgivable,
but considering our many years
of fighting side by side,
I beg for your mercy, My Lord.
My Lord.
I know I cannot escape death.
I have failed you.
Whether you kill me or not,
I submit to your judgment.
But I want to say,
those who wanted to kill you
were never us brothers,
but the imperial edict!
Please, My Lord,
don't make things difficult
for the brothers.
Everyone joined the Feiyu Guard—
a job so tough—
all for the sake of their families.
We're all risking our lives
in exchange for a salary.
If they have offended you in any way,
they were only following orders.
If you have grievances,
direct them at me, Ji Yan, alone.
The brothers have a hard life.
I beg for your forgiveness.
If that's the case,
I, Ji Yan,
am willing to cut off my own hand
to appease My Lord.
I submit myself to your judgment!
Everyone, get up.
Get up!
When did you
start colluding with the demons?
What kind of deals have you made?
Tell me everything in detail.
If you hide even the slightest detail,
I will show no mercy.
Thank you for sparing our lives, My Lord.
[Distinguish right from wrong]
My first encounter with the demons
began after Miss Xiao Yao
was captured and taken to Demons' Valley.
Back then, you had just been appointed
as the Demon Slayer of the Feiyu Guard
and posted bounty notices
to lure out the great demons.
That very night,
a demon calling himself Heiwu
approached me.
He offered to help the Feiyu Guard
eliminate the Demon King Hong Ye.
Now, on the first and fifteenth
of each month,
the demons
offer up some minor demons.
We escort them to
the Elixir Refining Chamber
in the West Garden to create elixirs.
With this arrangement,
we also earn rewards for our brothers
to support our families.
I never imagined
the Feiyu Guard has fallen so low.
My Lord!
Forgive my boldness.
But what we have between
the Feiyu Guard and the demons
is already the best we can have.
What are you talking about?
Only when soldiers
don't eliminate bandits completely,
will the court keep the soldiers employed.
My Lord.
Demons can never be completely eliminated.
The current arrangement,
where demons provide
some insignificant minor demons
for the Feiyu Guard to report as captures—
isn't this the best solution?
Besides you,
no one wants
the demons completely exterminated.
Since you became the Demon Slayer,
you've pushed everyone too hard.
Each of us
risks our lives day and night
without receiving any benefits.
We had no choice
but to join forces
with the demons against you.
My Lord,
the feud between humans and demons
ultimately means less than the lives
of our families.
We just want to protect those close to us.
If everyone were like you,
saving the world
while suffering
the tragic deaths of loved ones
and the torment
of souls unable to reincarnate,
what would be the point?
Even if all these brothers were gone,
and replaced with new ones,
the result would be the same.
I speak
from the bottom of my heart.
Please reconsider, My Lord!
Last night,
that woman who fought with you,
has she appeared again?
The Feiyu Guard and Imperial Guards
have searched the entire city
but found no trace of her.
However, that woman
has exceptional martial arts skills,
and she has
the demon-slaying blade with her.
She should be fine.
When you recover your power,
you must conjure
lots and lots of silver for me.
Okay.
I'll give you anything you want.
Xiao Yao.
I want to ask you something.
Yes, go ahead.
Dali...
is not coming back, is she?
You've been avoiding the subject
and I've been afraid to ask.
But the closer we get to Demons' Valley,
the more I think about her.
Dali...
has become the most beautiful flower
among all blossoms.
That's good.
She always loved beauty.
Dali has gone far away for cultivation.
I'm sure we'll see her again someday.
Yes.
My Lord,
are you all right?
I suddenly feel uneasy.
I just need to rest here for a while.
You all go ahead.
Yes, sir.
Yes.
If one is not a spirit,
can they still use spirit arts?
No.
You've been carrying the Exquisite Heart
you brought back
from the Realm of Mist and Void.
It's right here.
I was so arrogant.
I kept saying I would take care of you.
But in the end, because of me,
you've taken the same path as Lu Tong.
I, Bingzhu,
carry the empty title of demon slayer,
but in the end, I couldn't save anyone.
What's wrong with you?
Why do I still feel heartache?
Wasn't replacing
my heart with the Exquisite Heart
supposed to make me feel nothing?
You were originally a kind person.
Even if you changed your heart,
it wouldn't change who you are.
No!
I am a demon,
a spirit...
I used spirit arts to bewitch people.
Humans can be good or bad—
same goes for spirits and demons.
What corrupts both humans and demons
is desire.
Half of my life has been in vain.
I no longer care about
right or wrong in this world.
My only wish is
for the day when we
stand against each other
to never come.
If that moment truly comes,
I beg you...
Promise me,
will you?
please?
A-Aren't we going back to Demons' Valley?
Where is this place?
The barrier at the riverbank
must have been destroyed.
There will certainly be
many Feiyu Guards stationed there.
I once set
a hidden barrier here
that only I can open.
I thought
I'd never need to use it.
My Lord, your foresight is formidable.
In that case,
we can rush in
and kill them all,
catching them off guard.
Then after that...
Kill what?
If we fight,
there will be casualties.
My Lord is indeed amazing,
but he is a lord
who truly cares about the demons.
He would hope
to take back Demons' Valley
without any bloodshed.
Although I don't quite understand,
I think that makes sense.
What should we do next?
Let me check the situation.
We can discuss it later
after figuring out their formation.
Take His Lordship
and hide somewhere safe.
Hide?
Yes.
Not hide.
It's rest.
My Lord has been working hard these days
and needs to rest first.
Just find a place
where no one will discover you.
But even I don't feel tired.
You've been eating,
drinking, and sleeping the whole way,
why would you be tired?
That's true.
I'll go ahead and wait for you.
Xiao Yao.
As the Demon Lord,
I have my responsibilities.
Though I've lost my power,
no one knows Demons' Valley
better than I do.
I don't want to hide.
Besides, Heiwu fears me the most.
The Feiyu Guard has been searching
for the Kunlun Mirror.
As long as they want something,
we can find a way
to defeat them one by one.
But...
It's here!
We're back!
Let's go back and fight now!
We'll kill them all—
Oh no,
today is the first day of the month.
I...
Mr. Wu Huan!
Look, there's a donkey.
Go!
As a bamboo stick,
you can't even escape in a bamboo forest.
You deserve to be caught
and made into mats and baskets.
Go ahead.
Keep running.
Stop!
My Lord?
My Lord!
My Lord, you're finally back!
He wants to capture us
and hand us over to the Feiyu Guard.
Did you not die from poisoning?
It was the Dreamshard Immortal who died.
Why should I fear poison?
You previously framed Xiao Yao
and led the Feiyu Guard
to massacre Demons' Valley.
I was too busy to kill you then,
which allowed you to harm your own kind
with Heiwu today.
This is truly a capital offense.
Go back and tell Heiwu.
I never wished
to see our kind harm each other.
I'll give him one chance.
Release our kind immediately,
leave Youning Cave,
and get out of Demons' Valley.
But if he dares to persist in his folly,
I will show no more mercy.
I will make sure your evil deeds
are paid back a thousandfold.
Wu Huan.
The count is off today.
These few minor demons
are far from enough.
Are you underestimating
the Feiyu Guard's abilities?
There are more.
They're all behind.
Go.
That looks like the Demon King Hong Ye.
Are you sure?
Are you certain it's the Demon King?
Yes.
I've seen him before
when I raided Demons' Valley
with the Demon Slayer.
Luoluo.
Bamboo.
Are they the ones who have been
coming to Demons' Valley
to capture demons?
-Yes!
Very well.
With My Lord here today,
are you going to make them
pay for their crimes in blood?
I'll count to three.
If I can still see you then,
you'll have only your bad luck to blame.
Three.
Go!
Two.
Go.
Run!
Run! Hurry!
W-Why?
Hong Ye, let's go.
Captain!
Captain.
Why are we running?
Don't be stupid. You said it yourself.
That's the Demon King.
But he didn't chase us.
Last time we saw him, he was formidable.
Flying through the sky,
burrowing underground,
killing anyone in his way.
But just now he seemed
somehow different.
He was all talk.
He didn't use his power at all.
If that's the case,
his power might be...
Gone.
This is our chance
to defeat the Demon King
and achieve great merit!
What kind of hunter runs away
after spotting his prey?
Let's go back!
Let's see what powers he really has.
Let's go!
Go!
Move!
Let's go!
W-Wait.
W-Why are we running?
Didn't His Lordship say
when he counts to three, we would...
Take our revenge?
Yeah.
Xiao Yao.
Take Bamboo and Luoluo
and leave first.
I'll deal with Wu Huan.
Wait!
Don't worry.
I have a way to lure him away.
Go quickly.
No.
This is the only way.
Otherwise all of us
will be trapped here.
You still can't go.
I have a plan
that can both repel the enemy
and keep everyone safe.
He's gone indeed.
He must've gotten injured when fighting
the Dreamshard Immortal,
which depleted all his power.
Everyone spread out and search carefully.
Capturing the Demon King
brings far greater merit
than catching thousands of minor demons.
Go now!
Yes!